<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="basic_languageswitcher" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <title>Language Switcher</title>
  <para>The Keyman Language Switcher is a single popup menu to let you rapidly switch between any installed Keyman keyboard, Windows language or Windows layout.</para>
  <para>
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
	  <!--Makara doesn't know how to capture these; they don't seem to be an issue because the image should look pretty much similar.-->
        <imagedata fileref="desktop_images/languageswitcher.png"></imagedata>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
  </para>  
 
  <bridgehead>Opening and Using the Language Switcher</bridgehead>
  <para>To open and use the Keyman Language Switcher </para>
  <orderedlist>
  <listitem>
    <para>Press the Language Switcher hotkey to bring up the Language Switcher. If you are using the default Language Switcher hotkey (<keycap>Left.Alt</keycap> + <keycap>Shift</keycap>) or another hotkey with <keycap>Alt</keycap>, you will need to press and HOLD the <keycap>Alt</keycap> part of the hotkey and press and RELEASE the last key in the hotkey to use the Language Switcher. When you release <keycap>Alt</keycap>, the Language Switcher will close.</para>
	<note><para>By default, the Language Switcher hotkey is <keycap>Left.Alt</keycap> + <keycap>Shift</keycap>.  You can view or change the current Language Switcher hotkey from the <link linkend='basic_hotkeys_tab'>Hotkeys tab</link> of Keyman Configuration.</para></note> 
    <para>
        <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="desktop_images/languageswitcher-small.png" />
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject>
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Navigate the Language Switcher using the arrow keys or by pressing <keycap>Shift</keycap> to select your Keyman keyboard.</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Release the Language Switcher hotkey or press <keycap>Enter</keycap> to activate the selected keyboard and close the Language Switcher. You will notice the Keyman menu icon change to the icon of your Keyman keyboard. This means your Keyman keyboard is on.</para>
   </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
    
<bridgehead>Related Topics</bridgehead>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="basic_traymenu"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="basic_hotkeys_tab"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>  
</section>
