<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="about_welcome">
  <title>Welcome to Keyman</title>

  <para>Thank you for installing Keyman. Whether you're a new or returning user, we believe you will appreciate the significant enhancements in this latest version of Keyman.</para>
  
  <bridgehead>What is Keyman?</bridgehead>
  <para>Keyman is a keyboard application that makes it easy for you to type in your language in all your favourite Windows programs and across the Web. Keyman is used by more than a million people to type in over 1000 languages and counting.</para>
  <para>Keyman remaps your hardware keyboard to any one of hundreds of virtual keyboards, available for download from the <ulink url="https://keyman.com/">Keyman Website</ulink> and around the Web. If you cannot find a keyboard for your language, we offer the companion application <ulink url="https://keyman.com/developer/">Keyman Developer</ulink>. Keyman Developer is a powerful software solution for creating the perfect Keyman keyboard to suit your needs.</para>
  <para>Keyman features seamless integration with your Windows operating system and the Windows language bar. You can use Keyman keyboards with Keyman in almost any Windows or Web application. Try it in office software like Word or Excel; browsers like Firefox or Internet Explorer; design programs like Adobe InDesign; and email services like Outlook or Gmail.</para>
  <para>Keyman fully supports <ulink url="http://www.unicode.org/">Unicode</ulink> and legacy standards and can be used with all standard hardware keyboards, making it the perfect solution for typing in any language on your computer.</para>
  <para>A list of features in Keyman is available <link linkend="about_whatsnew">here</link>.</para>
  <para>
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <!--the image here is very much similar to the one we have in version 10.0; we could probably keep it.-->
		<imagedata fileref="desktop_images/osk_keyboard.png"></imagedata>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
  </para>
  
<bridgehead>Related Topics</bridgehead>
 <itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
   <para>
    <xref linkend="about_whatsnew"></xref>
   </para>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
   <para>
    <xref linkend="about_requirements"></xref>
   </para>
  </listitem>
 </itemizedlist>
 
</section>