<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 2019 Daniel Glassey <wdg@debian.org> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.keyman.config</id>
  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <project_group>Keyman</project_group>
  <developer id="org.sil.keyman">
    <name>SIL Global</name>
  </developer>
  <icon type="remote" width="96" height="96">https://keyman.com/cdn/dev/img/keyman-logo.png</icon>
  <name>Keyman for Linux</name>
  <summary>Keyman makes it possible for you to type in over 2,000 languages</summary>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-info">mild</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>

  <description>
    <p>
Keyman makes it possible for you to type in over 2,000 languages on Windows, macOS, Linux,
iPhone, iPad, Android tablets and phones, and even instantly in your web browser. With the
world's most powerful keyboarding engine, intuitive and rapid text input is now possible in
your language, and for over 99% of the global population's mother tongues!
</p>
    <p>
Originally created in 1993 to type Lao on Windows, Keyman is now a free and
open source keyboarding platform which allows anyone to write and use a keyboard layout
for their language. Keyman is available for many platforms, including Windows,
macOS, iOS, Android, Linux and the web.
</p>
    <p>
Keyboard layouts are defined with a clear and easy to understand keyboard
grammar. Keyman's contextual input model means keyboard layouts can be
intelligent and make it simple to type even the most complex languages.
Keyboard layouts are distributed through an open catalog to all major desktop
and mobile platforms.
</p>
    <p>
 Install, uninstall and view information about Keyman keyboard packages.
    </p>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">km-config.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>The Keyman for Linux configuration window with a keyboard welcome window.</caption>
      <image type="source" width="920" height="518">https://keyman.com/go/linux/17.0/linux-configuration.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <url type="homepage">https://keyman.com/linux/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/keymanapp/keyman/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://help.keyman.com/</url>
  <url type="faq">https://community.software.sil.org/c/keyman</url>
  <url type="contact">https://keyman.com/contact/</url>
  <url type="donation">https://donate.keyman.com/</url>
</component>
