<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="help.xsl" ?>
<ContextHelp>

  <LanguageReference Name="group">
    <p>(TODO: add  documentation on group)</p>
  </LanguageReference>

  <Form Name="context/character-map">
    <Control Name="editFilter" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>The Filter allows a user to reduce the number of characters displayed in the character map. The standard filter options used are by font name or block name.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="grid" Title="Character Map">
      <p>The Character Map Grid displays each character in a square, with a visual representation of the character and the Unicode value displayed at the bottom of the square. Each font group is divided into a block headed by the font name.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdFilter" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>The Filter allows a user to reduce the number of characters displayed in the
      character map. The standard filter options used are by font name or block name.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="rbRange" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>The filter format for a range is: [U+]XXXX-[U+]YYYY, where U+ is optional,
      XXXX is the starting Unicode value and YYYY is the finishing Unicode value.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editRangeStart" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>The filter format for a range is: [U+]XXXX-[U+]YYYY, where U+ is optional,
      XXXX is the starting Unicode value and YYYY is the finishing Unicode value.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editRangeStop" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>The filter format for a range is: [U+]XXXX-[U+]YYYY, where U+ is optional,
      XXXX is the starting Unicode value and YYYY is the finishing Unicode value.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="rbName" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>The Filter allows a user to reduce the number of characters displayed in the
      character map. The standard filter options used are by font name or block name.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdCharactersInCurrentFontOnly" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p> "&gt;" placed at the start of an entry will only show characters in the currently
      selected Character Map font. This is helpful when trying to determine which characters
      a given font supports.</p><br></br>
      <p>Example: &gt;LAO </p><br></br>
      <p>finds all characters with names starting in "LAO" in the current font</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdBlock" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p> "&lt;" placed at the start of an entry will search Unicode block names instead of
      character names. This is helpful when searching for characters within related
      blocks</p><br></br>
      <p>Example:  &lt;Thai </p><br></br>
      <p>finds the Thai Unicode block</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdStar" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>Using "*" in an entry serves as a wildcard for any number of places in that entry.
      For example, searching for "greek*alpha" will find characters whose Unicode names begin
      with the word "Greek" and contain the word "Alpha" any number of places later.
      This is helpful when searching for characters that share a common element in
      their names (e.g. capital).</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdQuestionMark" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>Using "?" anywhere in an entry serves as a wildcard for that single place in the entry.
      For example, searching for "s???e" will return both the SPACE and the SMILE characters,
      among others.</p><br></br>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdRange" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>Example: 1000-119F </p><br></br>
      <p>finds all characters between U+1000 and U+119F (inclusive) -
      the Myanmar alphabet in this case</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdSet" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>Example: LATIN * LETTER [AEIOU] </p><br></br>
      <p>finds all all Latin A,E,I,O or U vowel combinations</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdDollar" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>"$" placed at the end of an entry will match from the end of a Unicode character name.
      This option works best when used with "*" or "?".</p><br></br>
      <p>Example: LATIN * LETTER A$ </p><br></br>
      <p>finds only "a" and "A"</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdOK" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>Click OK to save changes and close the dialog.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdCancel" Title="Character Map Filter">
      <p>Click Cancel to close the dialog without saving changes.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <!-- ========================================================================
       Keyboard Editor
       ======================================================================== -->

  <Form Name="context/keyboard-editor">

    <!-- Details tab -->
    <Control Name="editName" Title="Keyboard Name">
      <p>The name of the keyboard is displayed in Keyman Configuration, in the tray menu and in many other places.  It should be a descriptive
      name, in any language, but remember that some applications may use a font that does not include the language you are writing the
      keyboard name in.  Don't include a version number, help information or hotkey in the name.</p>

      <p>This corresponds to the following source line:</p>
      <div class="code">store(&amp;name) 'My Keyboard'</div>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="clbTargets" Title="Targets">
      <p>Specifies the platforms for which this keyboard is designed. Where possible, use more generic targets, for example, use
      <div class="code">mobile</div> instead of both <div class="code">androidphone</div> and <div class="code">iphone</div>.
      preference, use <div class="code">any</div>.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cbType" Title="Character Set">
      <p>Your keyboard should be either Unicode or Codepage based.  Most keyboards today will be Unicode.  If you are designing in the source editor,
      you can create a keyboard that is includes both Unicode and Codepage (or "ANSI") rules.</p>

      <p>This corresponds to either of the following source lines:</p>
      <div class="code">
        begin ANSI &gt; use(main)<br />
        begin Unicode &gt; use(main)
      </div>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editCopyright" Title="Copyright">
      <p>Copyright details for the keyboard are displayed when the keyboard is installed.  They can also be viewed in Keyman Configuration.</p>

      <p>This corresponds to the following source line:</p>
      <div class="code">store(&amp;copyright) '© 2006 My Company'</div>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editMessage" Title="Message">
      <p>The message provides some additional information to a user of your keyboard, when they install the keyboard.</p>

      <p>This corresponds to the following source line:</p>
      <div class="code">store(&amp;message) 'Here is a message about a keyboard'</div>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="memoComments" Title="Comments">
      <p>In this field, enter information about the keyboard for your own reference.  These comments will only be visible in the
      source file, and not to users of your keyboard.</p>

      <p>The comments are placed at the top of the source file, e.g.:</p>
      <div class="code">
        c Version 1.2 - fixed a bug with the 'k' key<br/>
        c Version 1.1 - improved matching on vowels<br/>
        c Version 1.0 - initial version
      </div>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editKeyOutputText" Title="Output Character(s)">
      <p>To select another key in the keyboard, either:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Click on the key with the mouse, or</li>
        <li>Press and release the Ctrl key to choose with the keyboard</li>
      </ul>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="chkKMWRTL" Title="Keyboard is right-to-left">
      <p>Select this option to tell KeymanWeb to flag text entered by this keyboard as right-to-left (e.g. Arabic, Hebrew)</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editKMWHelpText" Title="Help Text">
      <p>A simple line of text to show under the On Screen Keyboard in KeymanWeb.  Can contain HTML formatting and links.  Mutually exclusive with the Help File box</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editKMWHelpFile" Title="Help File">
      <p>More complex help can be included by including an external file.  See the European Latin keyboard in Samples for a comprehensive example.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdKMWBrowseHelpFile" Title="Browse Help File">
      <p>Choose a help file to include in the keyboard</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdCompileKeymanWeb" Title="Compile to Web">
      <p>Compiles the keyboard for KeymanWeb.  Two output files will be generated: [filename].js and [filename]_load.js.  The KeymanWeb Tutorial
      contains more information about the difference between the two output files.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdTestKeymanWeb" Title="Test KeymanWeb Keyboard">
      <p>Tests your KeymanWeb keyboard in an Internet Explorer embedded window</p>
    </Control>

    <!-- Layout tab -->
    <!-- Icon tab -->
    <Control Name="cmdbitmapChange" Title="Change" TopicName="context/keyboard-editor#toc-icon-tab">
      <p>The Change option allows the editing of the icon filename.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdExport" Title="Export" TopicName="context/keyboard-editor#toc-icon-tab">
      <p>The Export option allows the exporting of the new image to a selected location.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdImport" Title="Import" TopicName="context/keyboard-editor#toc-icon-tab">
      <p>The import option allows for the loading of an existing icon from a selected location.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="panEdit" Title="Icon Editor" TopicName="context/keyboard-editor#toc-icon-tab">
      <p>The toolbox allows for the changing of the colours, addition of text and shapes.  It also allows for the moving of the icon around the canvas and also a preview of the icon is displayed.</p>
    </Control>

    <!-- On-Screen tab: see context/keyboard-editor#toc-on-screen-tab -->
    <!-- Touch Layout tab: see context/keyboard-editor#toc-touch-layout-tab -->
    <!-- Source tab -->
    <!-- Compile tab -->

    <Control Name="chkCustomOnScreenKeyboard" Title="Include">
      <p>A custom on screen (visual) keyboard can be included with your new keyboard. Check this option to display the on screen keyboard and options available.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="chkLayoutDisplay102key" Title="European Keyboards">
      <p>On European Keyboards a 102nd key is added.  This allows you to map a character on the 102nd key.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="chkIncludeTaskbarIcon" Title="Taskbar">
      <p>This option allows the user to choose whether the keyboard icon is displayed on the taskbar and to customise the look of the icon. Check the Include Icon on the Taskbar to display the icon bitmap editor.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="chkSplitCtrlAlt" Title="Right Ctrl/Alt">
      <p>Allows for more combinations and also leaves the left Ctrl and Alt keys for general keyboard shortcuts, for example Ctrl C for Copy and Ctrl V for Paste.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdAddToProject" Title="Project">
      <p>This option adds the keyboard to the current active project.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdCompile" Title="Compile Keyboard">
      <p>Select this option to begin the compiling of the keyboard. The success of the compile is displayed at the bottom of the screen.  If errors are displayed, click on the Start Debugging button.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdInsertCopyright" Title="">
      <p>Insert Copyright</p>
      <p>This allows for the insertion of a copyright symbol if needed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdInstall" Title="Install">
      <p>Install the compiled keyboard on to the computer.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="lbDebugHosts" Title="Debug Hosts">
      <p>To test on other platforms, open one of the debug host addresses
      on your device.  Your device will need to be on the same network as
      this computer.</p>

      <p>You can test within the web browser on your device, or in the
      native app if you have it installed: just click the Install
      button on the debugger web page.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdSendURLsToEmail" Title="Send URLs to Email">
      <p>The Send to email function makes it easier to open the addresses
      on your mobile device without having to enter them manually.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdOpenContainingFolder2" Title="Open Containing Folder">
      <p>This option will open the folder that contains all the files saved for the new keyboard project.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdStartDebugging" Title="Start Debugging">
      <p>This option will allow for the debugging of a keyboard that could not be compiled and specific errors are displayed. It will direct the user to the source code of the keyboard file.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdUninstall" Title="Uninstall">
      <p>Uninstall the keyboard from the computer.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdUpload" Title="Upload">
      <p>This option allows the user to upload the compiled keyboard to Tavultesoft website to allow the sharing of the keyboard files.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdVKChange" Title="Change">
      <p>The change button allows the change of the filename and/or location of the on screen keyboard.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editCharacterSet" Title="Unicode">
      <p>Your keyboard should be either Unicode or Codepage based. Most keyboards today will be Unicode. If you are designing in the source editor, you can create a keyboard that is includes both Unicode and Codepage (or "ANSI") rules.</p>
      <p>This corresponds to either of the following source lines:</p>
      <p>begin ANSI &gt; use(main)</p>
      <p>begin Unicode &gt; use(main)</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editComments" Title="Message">
      <p>The message provides some additional information to a user of your keyboard, when they install the keyboard.</p>
      <p>This corresponds to the following source line:</p>
      <p>store(&amp;message) 'Here is a message about a keyboard''</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editCopyright" Title="Keyman Configuration">
      <p>Copyright details for the keyboard are displayed when the keyboard is installed. They can also be viewed in Keyman Configuration.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editKeyOutputCode" Title="Unicode Character Value">
      <p>If the Unicode value is known, enter the value and the corresponding character will be displayed on the key.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editMessage" Title="Message">
      <p>To add additional details about the keyboard. The message will be displayed when the keyboard is selected in Keyman Configuration.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editOuputCharacters" Title="Release">
      <p>To select another key in the keyboard, either:</p>
      <p>Click on the key with the mouse, or</p>
      <p>Press and release the Ctrl key to choose with the keyboard</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editVKFileName" Title="">
      <p>KVK Filename</p>
      <p>Displays the file path and file name of the Keyman Visual Keyboard (KVK). Press the END key on your keyboard to view the filename or click on the Change button to change the filename and location.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/keyboard-editor#toc-on-screen-tab">
    <Control Name="chkVKDisplayUnderlyingChars" Title="Display Underlying Character Layouts">
      <p>If selected, then the visual keyboard will only be used if the current underlying layout is active. </p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="chkVKInclude102key" Title="">
      <p>Display 102nd Key</p>
      <p>On European Keyboards a 102nd key is added.  This allows you to map a character on the 102nd key.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="chkVKSplitCtrlAlt" Title="Right Ctrl/Alt">
      <p>Allows for more combinations and also leaves the left Ctrl and Alt keys for general keyboard shortcuts, for example Ctrl C for Copy and Ctrl V for Paste.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdBrowseKeyBitmap" Title="Browse button">
      <p>This allows for a bitmap/picture to be displayed on the selected key. Click on the Browse button to select the bitmap.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdExportOnScreenKeyboard" Title="XML">
      <p>Export the keyboard to other file formats (HTML, BMP, or PNG), for use in documentation. Export the structure of the keyboard to XML format for automated processing. </p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdImportOnScreenKeyboard" Title="Import">
      <p>Import an existing on screen keyboard layout.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdVKImportKMX" Title="Layout">
      <p>Use the same layout as the new keyboard, assigning the same characters to the same keyboard letters.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editVKKeyText" Title="Text">
      <p>Allows the user to enter text to be displayed on the selected key.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/keyboard-editor#toc-touch-layout-tab">
    <Control Name="cefwp" Title="Touch Layout Editor">
      <p>The Touch Layout tab is used to create the visible representation of the keyboard layout for touch devices. It works similarly to the On Screen Keyboard Editor conceptually, but has a number of additional features specific to touch. Keys on the touch layout trigger rules within the normal Keyman keyboard; if no rule is defined for a given key, it will be given output if it has a standard code beginning with <code>K_</code>, or if it is a Unicode value code, starting with <code>U_</code>.</p>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="help:guides/develop/touch-keyboard-tutorial">Read the guide on developing touch layouts</a></li>
      </ul>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/must-include-debug">
    <Control Name="*" Title="Keyman Developer Debugger 'Include Debug Information' Confirmation Screen">
      <p>Keyman Developer Debugger</p>
      <p>Debug information must be included in the compile keyboard before the debugger process can be started. From the Keyboard menu select Include Debug Information. The debug information will display the error sources when compiling.</p>
      <p>The debugger can be used without the debug information by clicking on Test without debugger.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/new-file-details">
    <Control Name="*" Title="New File">
      <p>Enter the name for your new keyboard. Click on the Browse button to change the location of the new keyboard.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/package-editor">
    <Control Name="cbImageFile" Title="Image File">
      <p>You can include an image file that will be displayed to the left of the install details when the package is installed. This image should be 140 pixels wide and 250 pixels high.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cbReadmeFile" Title="Readme file">
      <p>The readme file can be displayed after the installation of the keyboard package, but can also be accessed from the keyboard folder at a later time. The file must be loaded under the Files tab, add option before being able to be selected from the drop down list.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cbStartMenuProgram" Title="Shortcut Program" />
    <Control Name="chkCreateStartMenu" Title="Start menu">
      <p>This option will allow you to create a folder on the Start menu when the keyboard package is installed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="chkStartMenuUninstall" Title="Uninstall">
      <p>The uninstall shortcut will be added automatically to the shortcut menu list when the package is installed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdAddFile" Title="Add Files">
      <p>This option allows the user to add new files to the package.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdDeleteStartMenuEntry" Title="Delete">
      <p>To delete the selected shortcut menu item from the Start menu folder.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdInsertCopyright" Title="Insert Copyright">
      <p>This allows for the insertion of a copyright symbol if needed.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cbReadMe" Title="Read Me Details">
      <p>A readme file can be a text file (ANSI, UTF-8, or UTF-16), or an HTML file (recommended).  Other file types are also acceptable,
      but the package installer will load the file in a separate program.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cbKMPImageFile" Title="Package Image">
      <p>You can include an image file that will be displayed to the left of the install details when the package is
        installed.  This image should be 140 pixels wide and 250 pixels high.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdTestPackage" Title="Test Package">
      <p>You should try installing your package on your system before distributing it, to ensure that all files are
      installed correctly.  If you can, try installing your package on several different machines.</p>
    </Control>

    <!-- Compile Page -->

    <Control Name="editOutPath" Title="Compile">
      <p>Displays the output path and filename of the file when the package is compiled.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdCompileInstaller" Title="Compile Installer">
      <p>Creates a self-extracting installer consisting of the package plus Keyman or another Keyman Engine product that was created with the Branding Pack.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editInstallerOutputFilename" Title="Installer Output Filename">
      <p>Displays the output filename and path for the self-extract installer.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdInstallWith" Title="Select Product Installer">
      <p>Chooses a product installer, such as the Keyman installation source.  You can download Keyman installers from keyman.com.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdAddToProject" Title="Add to Project">
      <p>This option allows the user to add the compile package to the project, keeping all files together in the one location.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdBuildPackage" Title="Compile Package">
      <p>This option checks the package has all the required files and for any errors.  The success of the compilation is displayed at the bottom of the screen.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdInstall" Title="Install Package">
      <p>This option will install the package on the computer. A message will be displayed as to the success of the install.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdNewStartMenuEntry" Title="New">
      <p>To add a new menu item to the list of shortcuts to be displayed in the Start menu folder created when the keyboard package is installed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdOpenContainingFolder" Title="Open Containing Folder">
      <p>Opens the source folder of the selected file.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdOpenContainingFolder2" Title="Open Containing Folder">
      <p>This option will open the folder the selected package is located in.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdOpenFile" Title="Edit">
      <p>This option allows the user to edit the selected file if the appropriate editor is available.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdRemoveFile" Title="Remove Files">
      <p>This option allows the user to remove a selected file from the list.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdUninstall" Title="Uninstall Package">
      <p>This option will uninstall the package from the computer. A message will be displayed as to the success of the uninstall.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="cmdUpload" Title="Upload">
      <p>This option will enable the developer to upload the package to the Tavultesoft website.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editFilePath" Title="Path">
      <p>Displays the location of the selected file.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editFileType" Title="">
      <p>File Type</p>
      <p>Enter the details of the file type being added to the keyboard package.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editInfoAuthor" Title="Author's">
      <p>Enter the name of the author or authors of the keyboard package.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editInfoCopyright" Title="Copyright">
      <p>Enter the copyright details of the keyboard package This information will be displayed with the version, author and message information when the package is installed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editInfoEmail" Title="Email address">
      <p>Enter the contact email address for the keyboard package.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editInfoName" Title="Package Name">
      <p>Package Name is the name that will be displayed when the package is installed. It should be a descriptive name, in any language, but remember that some applications may use a font that does not include the language you are writing the keyboard name in. Don't include a version number, help information or hotkey in the name.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editInfoVersion" Title="Package Version">
      <p>The version number allows the user to check whether they have the latest version of the keyboard.  The format should be 'major.minor[.subversion]'.  Each number should be an integer, and you should avoid non-integer version strings.  See help for more details.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editInfoWebSite" Title="Website">
      <p>The website details for the keyboard package if available.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editStartMenuDescription" Title="Start">
      <p>The text to be displayed for the selected file as a menu item in the Start up folder that is created when the package is installed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="editStartMenuParameters" Title="Shortcut Parameters" />
    <Control Name="editStartMenuPath" Title="">
      <p>Start Menu Path</p>
      <p>Enter the path of the start menu to be displayed when the keyboard package is installed.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="lbFiles" Title="Package Files">
      <p>This will display all the files that have been added to the keyboard package.  It allows for the addition and removal of files, the entering of file details and the editing of any of the files listed if the appropriate editor is available.</p>
    </Control>
    <Control Name="memoFileDetails" Title="Details">
      <p>This option allows the user to enter details and other additional information about the selected file.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/project">
    <Control Name="*" Title="Project Manager">
      <p>The Project Manager allows you to manage all the files related to a keyboard layout in a single location.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/new-model-project-parameters">
    <Control Name="editAuthor" Title="Author Name">
      <p>The name of the developer of the keyboard. This is either your full name or
      the organization you're creating a model for.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editModelName" Title="Model Name">
      <p>We recommend the name of the language, dialect, or community that this model is
      intended for. The name must be written in all the Latin letters or Arabic numerals.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editCopyright" Title="Copyright">
      <p>Who owns the rights to this model and its data? Typically,
      you can use the automatically generated default value: © 2024 Your Full Name or
      Your Organization.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editFullCopyright" Title="Full copyright">
      <p></p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editVersion" Title="Version">
      <p>If this is the first time you've created a lexical model for you language, you should
      leave the version as 1.0. Otherwise, your version number must conform to the following
      rules: A version string made of major revision number.minor revision number.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="gridLanguages" Title="Languages">
      <p>Specifies the default BCP 47 language tags which will be added to the package
      metadata and project metadata.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdAddLanguage" Title="Add...">
      <p>To add a language tag, click the Add button to bring up the “Select BCP 47 Tag”
      dialog box.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdEditLanguage" Title="Edit...">
      <p>Click the Edit button to bring up the “Select BCP 47 Tag” dialog box again and edit the
      language tag.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdRemoveLanguage" Title="Remove">
      <p>Click the Remove button to delete the language tag.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editPath" Title="Path">
      <p>Specifies the base path where the project folder will be created.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdBrowse" Title="Browse...">
      <p>Browse for a folder or create a new folder to save the project to.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editAuthorID" Title="Author ID">
      <p>An Author ID is a unique identifier used to distinguish you from others
      who have the same or similar names. </p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cbBCP47" Title="Primary Language">
      <p>Choose your primary language which generated from the “Select BCP 47 Tag” dialog box.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editUniq" Title="Unique Name">
      <p>Enter a unique name of the model. You can use the name of the language, dialect,
      or community that this model is intended for.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editModelID" Title="Model ID">
      <p>Keyman automatically generates a model ID for you, given all the
      information already filled out. Model ID helps Keyman sorts and organizes
      different lexical models.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="editProjectFilename" Title="Project filename">
      <p>Specifies the base path where the project filename (.model.kpj) will be created.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="memoDescription" Title="Description">
      <p>Enter information about the model.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdCancel" Title="Cancel">
      <p>Click Cancel to close the dialog without saving changes.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/wordlist-editor">
    <Control Name="pages" Title="Wordlist tabs">
      <p>Wordlist tabs have two views: Design, and Code. Changes to one view are reflected
      immedaitely in the other view. Wordlist files should be stored in UTF-8 encoding
      (preferably without BOM), and tab-separated format.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="gridWordlist" Title="Wordlist tabs">
      <p>Every line of the tab-separated format file is shown here, and can be edited directly.
      For most wordlists, it will be more effective to use an external dictionary tool,
      such as SIL Fieldworks or SIL PrimerPrep to generate the wordlist from a text corpus,
      and use this tab just to preview the contents of the file.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdDeleteRow" Title="Wordlist tabs">
      <p>The Delete row button will delete the selected row in the wordlist.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdSortByFrequency" Title="Wordlist tabs">
      <p>The Sort by frequency button has no effect on the functioning of the wordlist,
      but can help you, the editor, by showing more common words earlier in the list.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/editor">
    <Control Name="cefwp" Title="Editor Window">
      <p>Editor windows in Keyman Developer supports standard Windows editing keystrokes.
      Many file formats, including .kmn, .kps, .xml, .html, .js and .json, support syntax
      highlighting. The text editor in Keyman uses the Monaco component from Visual Studio Code,
      so all the functionality available in that editor is also available here.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/character-identifier">
    <Control Name="gridFonts" Title="Character Identifier">
      <p>Attempt to identify the fonts on your system that will support the
      characters. You can quickly change fonts by clicking on a font name in the grid of
      identified fonts.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="sgChars" Title="Character Identifier">
      <p>Display the Unicode value of the selected character. </p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/messages">
    <Control Name="memoMessage" Title="Message Window">
      <p>The message window appears at the bottom of the screen, or floating in a toolbar
      window. It contains a list of error and warning messages returned from a compilation
      session. You can undock and dock the window by dragging its title bar.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/debug">
    <Control Name="memo" Title="Debugger input window">
      <p>The debugger input window is used for typing input to test the keyboard.
      In the top half of this window, input you type while testing your keyboard will be
      displayed, exactly the same as in use, with one exception: deadkeys will be shown
      visually with an OBJ symbol.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="sgChars" Title="Debugger input window">
      <p>The lower half of the window shows a grid of the characters to the virtual left
      of the insertion point, or the selected characters if you make a selection. Deadkeys
      will be identified in the grid. The grid will show characters in right-to-left scripts
      in backing store order, from left to right. If there are more characters in your text
      than can fit on the screen, then only those that fit will be shown in the grid.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/debug#toc-regression-testing">
    <Control Name="lbRegTestLog" Title="Regression Testing">
      <p>The idea in regression testing is to record a sequence of keystrokes and the
      output the keyboard produced, in order to test for the same behaviour when you
      make changes to the keyboard.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdRegTestStartStopLog" Title="Regression Testing">
      <p>Use Start Log/Stop Log to record the input and output. You can then use Start Test
      to run the test again, or go the Options menu to clear the log, or save or load a test,
      or use the batch mode to run several tests in a row. </p><br></br>
      <p>If the output produced while running a test is different to that stored when recording it,
      Keyman will halt the test on the line where the failure occurred, and activate
      Single Step mode.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdRegTestOptions" Title="Regression Testing">
      <p>In the Options menu, you can clear the log, save or load a test,
      or use the batch mode to run several tests in a row.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/debug#toc-state">
    <Control Name="cmdRestartDebugger" Title="State">
      <p>Pressing the Restart button will clear the keystroke log as well as
      clearing the text in the debug window. </p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="lbKeystrokeLog" Title="State">
      <p>This window shows the current keystroke state, and the sequence of
      keystrokes that were typed to arrive at this state. </p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/debug#toc-elements">
    <Control Name="lvElements" Title="Elements">
      <p>This shows the elements that make up rule currently being processed: the context,
      the key, and also what the output will be. If the rule uses stores, the contents of
      the store will be shown in the right-hand column, with the matched letter in red.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/debug#toc-call-stack">
    <Control Name="lbCallStack" Title="Call Stack">
      <p>Here all the lines that have been processed to this point are shown in a list.
      You can double-click on any entry in the list to display the line in the
      keyboard source.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/debug#toc-deadkeys">
    <Control Name="lbDeadkeys" Title="Deadkeys">
      <p>This lists all the deadkeys that are currently in the context.
      You can select one from the list to see it highlighted in the debug input box.
      This information can also be seen in the character grid in the lower half of
      the debugger input window.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/about-tike">
    <Control Name="cmdOK" Title="About Dialog">
      <p>The About dialog displays copyright and registration information for Keyman Developer,
      and has a link to the Keyman website.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>

  <Form Name="context/key-test">
    <Control Name="cmdInsert" Title="Virtual Key Identifier">
      <p>This dialog lets you check the virtual key code for any key combination (except Window reserved key combinations such as Alt + Tab). You can then insert the virtual key code into the last active edit window at the current cursor position.</p><br></br>
      <p>Press Shift + Enter to insert the current virtual key code into your source at the insertion point.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="chkLRDistinguish" Title="Virtual Key Identifier">
      <p>You can see the virtual key codes for left and right Ctrl / Alt combinations by checking the "Distinguish between left and right ctrl/alt" checkbox.</p>
    </Control>

    <Control Name="cmdClose" Title="Virtual Key Identifier">
      <p>To close the dialog, click the Close button or press Shift + Esc.</p>
    </Control>
  </Form>
</ContextHelp>