<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="basic_osk">
  <title>Keyman Toolbox - On Screen Keyboard</title>
  <para>The On Screen Keyboard tool of the <link linkend="basic_toolbox">Keyman Toolbox</link> shows the currently selected Keyman keyboard or Windows layout.</para>

  <para>
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="desktop_images/osk-tibetan.png"></imagedata>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
  </para>

  <note>Some Keyman keyboards do not contain an On Screen Keyboard view. You can find more help for those keyboards from the <link linkend='basic_usage'>Keyboard Usage tool</link> of the Keyman Toolbox.</note>
  
  <bridgehead>Opening the On Screen Keyboard</bridgehead>
  <para>To open the On Screen Keyboard:</para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
    <para>Click on the <guiicon>Keyman</guiicon> icon <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="desktop_images/icon-keyman.png" /></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>, on the Windows Taskbar near the clock.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>From the Keyman menu, select <guilabel>On Screen Keyboard</guilabel>.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>

  <bridgehead>Using the On Screen Keyboard</bridgehead>
  <para>You can use the On Screen Keyboard in two ways:</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>As a reference help, to teach you how to type all the letters in your Keyman keyboard.</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>To enter text by point-and-click.</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
  <para>To use the On Screen Keyboard as a reference help:</para>
	<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>Open the On Screen Keyboard</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>Type on your physical keyboard, using the On Screen Keyboard as a guide.</para>
			<note><para>The On Screen Keyboard will match the Shift state of your hardware keyboard. This means you can press any combination of <keycap>Shift</keycap>, <keycap>Ctrl</keycap>, <keycap>Alt</keycap> and <keycap>AltGr</keycap> (or <keycap>RightAlt</keycap>) and the On Screen Keyboard will change to show you the Shift state of your hardware keyboard.</para></note>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
  <para>To enter text using the On Screen Keyboard:</para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Position your text cursor where you want to type in your application.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>On the On Screen Keyboard, click <keycap>Shift</keycap>, <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> or <keycap>Alt</keycap> if you need them to type your desired character.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>On the On Screen Keyboard, click the key with the character you want to enter.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
      <para>When a Keyman keyboard is on, the black font on the keycaps shows the characters assigned to each key. The blue font on the keycaps shows the characters of the Windows layout currently associated with the Keyman keyboard.</para>
	  <para>When no Keyman keyboard is on, the blue font on the keycaps shows the characters of your active Windows layout.</para>
	  <note>Some Keyman keyboards do not have an On Screen Keyboard view. For keyboards designed phonetically, this is because there is not a simple 1-1 correspondence between each key and the letter you want to type. The <link linkend="basic_usage">Keyboard Usage tool</link> is often helpful for these keyboards and Keyman will switch to this view by default. This option can be changed in <link linkend="basic_options_tab">Keyman Configuration</link>.</note> 
	  
<bridgehead>Related Topics</bridgehead>
 <itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
   <para>
    <xref linkend="basic_toolbox"></xref>
   </para>
  </listitem>
  <listitem>
   <para>
    <xref linkend="basic_usage"></xref>
   </para>
  </listitem>
   <listitem>
   <para>
    <xref linkend="basic_options_tab"></xref>
   </para>
  </listitem>
 </itemizedlist>
 
</section>