<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="start_rtl">
  <title>How To - Type in Right-to-Left Languages</title>
  <para>If you will be typing in a right-to-left language (like Arabic, Farsi, Hebrew, or Yiddish) there are three things you should know before you get started.</para>
  <orderedlist>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Your computer must be set up for right-to-left language support. Keyman will automatically set up your computer for most Keyman keyboards that need right-to-left language support. However, you may need to manually adjust your settings for some Keyman keyboards. Otherwise, without right-to-left language support, letters in your right-to-left language might appear in the wrong order, not join correctly, or change after the spacebar is pressed.</para>
	  <para>To do this, simply associate the keyboard with a right-to-left Windows language (like Arabic). For instructions on associating a Keyman keyboard with a Windows language, see: <xref linkend="start_configure_computer"></xref></para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>If you will be using MS Office programs like Word, you should configure MS Office for your right-to-left language. For instructions, see: <xref linkend="start_configure_office"></xref></para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>Each time you start typing with a right-to-left Keyman keyboard, you may need to change the typing direction in the program you are using, from left-to-right to right-to-left. In most Windows programs (including MS Word, Internet Explorer, and Notepad), you can use the following shortcuts to switch direction:</para>  
	  <itemizedlist>
	    <listitem>
		  <para>For right-to-left, press: <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> + <keycap>Right.Shift</keycap></para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
   		  <para>For left-to-right, press: <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> + <keycap>Left.Shift</keycap></para>
		</listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>
	  <para>In Firefox:</para>
	  <itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>To toggle between right-to-left and left-to-right, press: <keycap>Ctrl</keycap> + <keycap>Shift</keycap> + <keycap>X</keycap></para>
		</listitem>
	  </itemizedlist>  
	</listitem>
  </orderedlist>	
  <bridgehead>Related Topics</bridgehead>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="start_configure_computer"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="start_download-install_keyboard"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="start_configure_office"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="start_font"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="basic_enable_keyboard"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>