<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="context_downloadkeyboard">
  <title>Download Keyboard from Tavultesoft Dialog</title>
  <para>Clicking on the <guibutton>Download Keyboard</guibutton> button will display the Download Keyboard from Tavultesoft dialog box:</para>
  <para>
    <inlinemediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images\context_downloadkeyboard_01.png"></imagedata>
      </imageobject>
    </inlinemediaobject>
  </para>
  <orderedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Search for a keyboard layout by selecting the language or country appropriate from the       dropdown boxes, and clicking <guibutton>Search</guibutton>.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>If the keyboard layout you want to install is available from the Tavultesoft       website, click the <guibutton>Install Keyboard</guibutton> button for that keyboard layout. You may also choose to download the keyboard layout without installing it by checking the <guibutton>Don't install, just download</guibutton> checkbox at the bottom of the dialog window.</para>
      <para>If the keyboard layout is not available on the Tavultesoft website, but has       a link to an external website, clicking on that link will open the external       website in your web browser. From here, locate the keyboard layout download link and click on it.       Depending on your browser, this may save the keyboard layout or package to your computer or       attempt to install it into <application>Keyman Desktop</application>. If it is saved to       your computer, see <link linkend="section.anchor.2">Installing a keyboard layout or package from a local folder.</link></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>When the <guilabel>Install Keyboard/Package </guilabel> dialog is displayed, click <guibutton>Install</guibutton> to install the keyboard layout or package.</para>
    </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <note>
    <para>If a keyboard layout with the same name is already installed, <application>Keyman Desktop</application> will     confirm whether you want to replace the old keyboard layout or cancel the installation.</para>
  </note>
  <tip>
    <para>This dialog connects to the Tavultesoft Website.  No personal information is sent to   Tavultesoft in this process.  The information in this dialog may not be displayed in the same   language as the rest of the application, as it comes from a variety of sources.</para>
  </tip>
  <bridgehead>Related Topics</bridgehead>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="context_configuration_keyboards"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="context_installkeyboard"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="guide_keyboard_install"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="guide_keyboard_unload"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="context_keyman"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>