<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="main_purchasing_keyman">
  <title>Purchasing Keyman Desktop</title>
  <bridgehead>Who must register?</bridgehead>
  <para>
    <application>Keyman Desktop</application>is made available as trial software.  You may use Keyman Desktop freely for up to 30 days for evaluation purposes.  After such time, you must purchase a licence to continue using Keyman Desktop or uninstall it. See the <link linkend="main_license">End User Licence and Services Agreement</link> for more information.  When you purchase a licence to continue using Keyman Desktop, you can enter this into the trial version, which will convert the trial version into the fully licensed version.</para>
  <bridgehead>How to Purchase</bridgehead>
  <para>
    <application>Keyman Desktop</application>can be purchased directly from Tavultesoft via the <ulink url="https://secure.tavultesoft.com/buy/">Tavultesoft Online Store</ulink> or from registered Tavultesoft agents.</para>
  <para>Clicking the <guibutton>Buy</guibutton> button on the splash screen will open the <ulink url="https://secure.tavultesoft.com/buy/">Tavultesoft Online Store</ulink> in your web browser.</para>
  <bridgehead>Pricing</bridgehead>
  <para>Current pricing can be obtained from the <ulink url="https://secure.tavultesoft.com/buy/">Tavultesoft Online Store</ulink>.</para>
  <bridgehead>Payment methods</bridgehead>
  <para>Available payment methods will differ depending on the seller you are purchasing       from, but if purchasing from Tavultesoft the recommended payment method is by       credit card over the Internet at the Tavultesoft Online Store. Other payment methods       available from the Tavultesoft Online Store are PayPal Online, Western Union,        Wire Transfer/Direct Deposit and Cheque/Money Order. For more information on these methods,       please visit the <ulink url="https://secure.tavultesoft.com/buy/">Tavultesoft Online Store</ulink> or contact Tavultesoft.</para>
  <bridgehead>Moving a licence to another computer</bridgehead>
  <para>You can move a licence to another computer, even after you have activated Keyman Desktop, by contacting Tavultesoft Support (<ulink url="mailto:support@tavultesoft.com">support@tavultesoft.com</ulink>)       with your licence details and a note about moving the licence and the reason for the move (for example,       purchasing a new computer, or replacing a computer that had a hardware failure).</para>
  <bridgehead>Related Topics</bridgehead>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="context_activate"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="context_manualactivate"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="guide_install"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        <xref linkend="context_splash"></xref>
      </para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</section>