<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<section id="main_whatsnew"><title>What's New in Keyman Desktop</title><itemizedlist><listitem>Keyman is now called Keyman Desktop.  This name change was made to better distinguish Keyman Desktop from Keyman Developer and KeymanWeb.</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>Changes in version 7.1</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Phonetic-style keyboard layouts display handy hints on how to use them in place of an on-screen keyboard (this is known as a Usage Page).</listitem><listitem>Getting Started now opens the Getting Started Tutorial - a text editor with instructions on how to start using Keyman Desktop.</listitem><listitem>The Font Helper tool shows all the fonts on your system that work with the selected keyboard layout.</listitem><listitem>Tips and hints are displayed at key points in the program, making Keyman Desktop easier to start using.</listitem><listitem>Improved language linking means that Keyman Desktop now handles switching languages as well as keyboard layouts - you can turn off the Language Bar completely in many cases!</listitem><listitem>The help and support documentation has been expanded and improved.</listitem><listitem>Keyboard layout help is more accessible.</listitem><listitem>The Keyman menu has been simplified.</listitem><listitem>The on screen keyboard can be configured to display automatically when a keyboard layout is selected.</listitem><listitem>The Character Map displays characters from Unicode 5.1.</listitem><listitem>Various bugs and performance issues have been fixed.</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>Changes in version 7.0</bridgehead><bridgehead>On Screen Keyboard</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Now supports non-Latin Windows keyboard layouts</listitem><listitem>Now resizable</listitem><listitem>Enhanced display with ClearType and font linking</listitem><listitem>Toolbar to switch keyboard layouts and access Keyman Desktop functions</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>On Screen Keyboard Character Map</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Powerful character map allows instant input of characters into active application</listitem><listitem>Displays all characters from Unicode 5.1</listitem><listitem>Filter characters by range, name, font and more</listitem><listitem>Exceptionally clear display with ClearType and font linking</listitem><listitem>Resizable character cells</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>User Interface Redesign</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Clearer user interface</listitem><listitem>Better presentation of keyboard layout information</listitem><listitem>Localisable: ability to translate the Keyman Desktop user interface into any language</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>Integrated Keyboard layout Downloads</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Download and install keyboard layouts from the Tavultesoft Keyboard Downloads Site in a couple of clicks</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>Modern COM API</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Control all aspects of Keyman Desktop from Windows Scripting, Visual Basic for Applications, or your application!</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>Simplified Registration</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Registration is a single licence key</listitem></itemizedlist><bridgehead>Modern installation and operating system support</bridgehead><itemizedlist><listitem>Windows Vista support</listitem><listitem>Windows Installer (.msi) for straightforward deployment</listitem><listitem>Checks for updates and downloads and installs patches automatically</listitem></itemizedlist></section>